Zeyu (Jack) Wang

jackywangmel96@gmail.com https://github.com/JackyWang96 www.linkedin.com/in/Jack-Wang-Mel

Career Profile

Full-time software developer with experience in Java, C#, JavaScript, and Salesforce CRM. The programming and problem-solving skills allow me to plan appropriate strategies to solve problems. Experience with Jira, Bitbucket tools and AWS to help deep understanding of project implementation and management process. A quick learner who can quickly adapt to different technology stacks and programming languages.

Technical Skills

- Programming language: Java SE11, JavaScript ES8, Python, C#, Typescript
- Frameworks: Django, React, Flask, React Native, ASP.NET Framework, npm/yarn
- Database: MySQL 8.0, Microsoft SQL Server 2016/2019, NoSQL, SOQL
- Version Control: GitHub, GitLab, Postman, Bitbucket, docker
- Task Management: Jira, Confluence, Trello, Teams, Bitbucket
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban
- OS: Windows, Linux
- Network protocols: TCP/UDP

Education

Master of Information Technology (Distributed Computing) The University of Melbourne

Jul 2019 - Dec 2021

Bachelor of Computer Information System Arizona State University

Aug 2015 - Dec 2018

(New American University Scholar Scholarship holder) 2015-2018

Work Experience

Software Developer (Full-time)

Jul 2022 - Now

Department of Education & Training, Victoria, Centric Innovations,

- ✓ Writing Apex Triggers and Apex Classes
 - ✓ Designing UI using Visualforce Pages.
 - ✓ Write complex SOQL, SOSL queries

Skilled in Salesforce platform (SFDC) development and implementation. Good Hands-on experience on native Force.com application (Apex, Java and Visualforce). For example, Knowledge on writing Apex (Java) Triggers and Apex (Java) Classes, Batch Apex, Bulk API. Furthermore, experienced in designing UI using Visualforce Pages. Designing high level UI using Html, CSS, Java script along with Visualforce tags and Apex (Java) controllers. Using SOQL, SOL queries across multiple objects within SFDC.

Associate System Tester (Contract Role)

Feb 2019 - Aug 2019

iFLYTEK

- ✓ Data warehouse developed and tested
- ✓ Optimized the SQL database
- ✓ JUnit for unit testing
- ✓ Database feature testing and stress testing

Optimized and tested the data warehouse for iFLYTEK's artificial intelligence product - voice assistant. Solved the **database query speed** problem. As a result, the SQL read speed changed from the original processing speed of 5.5 seconds to 3.2 seconds. In the testing section, I did **backup**, **restore**, **concurrency** testing, and large data volume testing. My tests help the company database reduce refactoring risk.

Engineering Code Contribution Tracker

Jul 2021 - Nov 2021

- Back-end (Python)
 - ✓ **RESTful APIs** implementation (Github, Scitools, Confluence)
 - ✓ Django frameworks build and configuration
 - ✓ MySQL database creation and data import
 - ✓ Curl and Postman test for the API
- Front-end (CSS, JavaScript, HTML, ES6)
 - ✓ React framework build and configuration
- Project Management (agile methodology)
 - ✓ Project architecture design by use

The project design for collecting raw data points of student GitHub check-ins, Confluence contributions, and JIRA activity to provide university coordinators and teaching staff with visual activity data for students. As a back-end developer, I am responsible for **Django** framework construction, **API design** and database connection. In the API design, use the official **REST API** plus token to obtain data. For example, use the **SHA-1** value in GitHub for **data query** and filtering. During the end of the project, the client was clearly impressed and commented that it was above and beyond his expectation.

Android app code design and development

July 2021-Nov 2021

- Back-end (Python)
 - ✓ Flask frameworks configuration
- Front-end (CSS, JAVASCRIPT, HTML, ES6)
 - ✓ React Native framework build and configuration
 - ✓ API tools test
 - ✓ Layout design and implement by Flexbox and reference React Native sub-library

I took part in a mobile app development project, which is sharing free textbook and tutorial book resources for school subjects to the college students. I implemented the app's front-end with **JavaScript (React Native framework)**. special mention that use React Native styles such as flex in front-end layout design. The product has been recognized by customers and additionally completed the comment function added by customers in the late term.

Distributed Shared Whiteboard Design

Mar 2021-June 2021

- Back-end (Java)
 - ✓ Distributed framework design
 - ✓ Protocols implementation
 - √ Thread synchronous management
- Front-end (Java-swing)
 - ✓ GUI design
 - ✓ Panel implementation by using Java.awt package and JOptionPane

Whiteboard project is to implement a shared Whiteboard application which allows numbers of clients to share the paint from different location. I designed the paint function by using the drawstring method in **Java.awt** package and use a **JOptionPane** to type the words. I was also involved in the design of a **multi-thread framework**. This framework helped whiteboard realize the real-time sharing and information interaction between different clients.

Volunteering Experience

Member of Coalition of international students

Aug 2018 - Dec 2019

Arizona State University - W. P. Carey School of Business

I am responsible for organizing a carnival-international night. This is an event that will be over 100 people. It provides communication opportunities for the school's international students. By applying for venues with schools, sponsors cooperate, international night can be held at the playground with free food and drinks. In the end, the project was held successfully and brought students a good event experience.